( rain pattering )
TEENAGED GIRL : I hate television .
Gives me headaches .
( woman on TV ) : ... makes your color-treated hair ...
You know , I heard there 's
so many magnetic waves traveling through the air
because of TV and telephones , that we 're losing , like
ten times as many brain cells as we 're supposed to .
Like , all the molecules in our heads are all unstable .
All the companies know about it
but they 're not doing anything about it .
It 's , like , a big conspiracy .
( sighing ) : You can pick something . I don 't care .
Say hello to luscious , full bod ...
You have any idea how many electro-rays
are traveling through our head every second ?
I got a better one .
Have you heard about this videotape
that kills you when you watch it ?
What kind of tape ?
A tape , a regular tape .
People rent it , I don 't know .
You start to play it
and it 's , like , somebody 's nightmare .
Then suddenly , this woman comes on
smiling at you , right ?
Seeing you through the screen ...
and as soon as it 's over ...
your phone rings .
Someone knows you 've watched it
and what they say is ...
" You will die in seven days "
and exactly seven days later ...
Who told you that ?
Somebody from Revere . I don 't ...
Who told you ?
What 's your problem ?
I 've watched it .
( sighing ) : It 's a story , Katie .
No , me and Josh , we saw it last weekend .
I thought you were with your parents .
I wanted to tell you .
You were with Josh all weekend ?
His friends got this place up in the mountains .
They were trying to record a football game .
I guess the reception was so bad ...
What are you talking about ?
Listen to me !
When we played the tape , the game wasn 't there .
It was ...
What ? Wh-What was it ?
It was something else .
We thought it was some kind of sick joke ...
and then the phone rang .
It was a week ago ...
one week ago tonight .
( chuckles nervously )
You 're just trying to scare me .
( gagging )
( gagging continuing )
Oh , my God , Katie !
Are you okay ?
Katie ... oh , my ...
( snickering )
You freak !
( laughing ) : You totally fell for it !
No .
So ... did you guys , you know , do anything ?
Like what ?
Oh , my God , you totally did !
You ho !
Tell me now !
( phone ringing )
( gasps )
( ticking )
( ringing continuing )
There really is a tape ?
( sighs )
This is so lame .
Wait , don 't !
Embrey residence .
( pants nervously )
( rain continuing )
Hello .
Hi , Mom .
( sighs angrily )
( chuckles )
Yeah , that was Becca .
My mom says hi . She 's glad you 're here .
Ask her where she keeps the Vicodin .
( chuckles )
Yeah , we 're about to go to sleep .
Okay . Yeah , I will .
Okay ! Okay , yeah , yeah , I will .
No , I won 't .
Bye , Mom .
( beeps )
( TV static blaring )
( static continuing )
Becca , quit being a bitch .
Where 's the remote ?
( rain continuing )
( TV static resumes )
( static continues )
Becca , quit it !
( whimpers )
( panting nervously )
( sighs )
( gasps )
( eerie rumbling )
( panting )
( whimpers softly )
( whimpers ) ( thump )
Becca , can you hear me ?
( panting )
( static hissing )
( hissing continuing )
( breathing nervously )
( high-pitched electronic whine )
( static blaring )
( rain continuing )
( rain pattering )
( distant door opens )
WOMAN : Don 't tell me what to write !
That asshole 's screaming for my attention
and I 'm not going to give it to him .
I am being objective !
Listen , Harvey , you punctilious prick
you touch my column
and I 'm coming down there and poking your eye out
with that little red pencil you like so much !
Harvey ?
Shit !
Hey ...
Hey .
Sorry I 'm late .
No worries .
I 'll wait in the car .
Have you got a moment , Ms. Keller ?
Um , sure .
Call me Rachel .
Please , sit down .
He certainly is very independent , isn 't he ?
Oh , yeah , he sure is .
I never have to tell him to do anything .
Well , if that 's a problem
you 'd be the first teacher in history to say so .
Ms. Keller ...
Rachel .
I know that Aidan recently lost his cousin ...
Yes , and I 'm doing what I can
to find him some good daycare . It 's just ...
Oh , no , that 's not what I meant .
By all means , take your time .
I know they were very close , Aidan and his cousin .
Yeah . They spent a few nights a week together .
Did he talk to you about her death ?
Well , like you said , he 's not the talkative type .
That doesn 't mean he has nothing to say .
He knows I 'm there .
Yes , I 'm sure he does
but he may be expressing himself in ... other ways .
I 'd like to show you something .
That 's his cousin .
That 's Katie .
Ms. Keller ... I 'm bothered by these drawings .
Listen , I appreciate your concern
but my son lost his best friend three nights ago .
He 's just trying to deal with it .
Yes , I understand , but these pictures ...
Are Aidan 's way of working it out ...
of expressing himself , like you said .
( keys jingling )
He 'll be okay .
You say she died three nights ago ?
Yeah , that 's right .
Aidan drew these last week .
â  ªâ  ª
What ?
Nothing .
Shall we read something ?
I 'm kind of tired .
Okay .
Sweet dreams .
We don 't have enough time .
Oh , honey , I know I 've been working a lot
and I 'm sorry
but I promise you , I 'm going to make it up to you .
I 'm not talking about that .
I 'm talking about time before we die .
You have lots of time .
So , you know when I 'm going to die ?
No .
No one does
but I know you don 't have to worry about it .
Katie knew .
She told me .
Katie told you she was going to die ?
She said she didn 't have enough time .
Good night , Rachel .
( traffic passing )
RACHEL : Oh , shit !
( grunting )
Aidan ...
Goddamn it !
Honey ? !
Have you seen my black dress ?
Aidan ?
Have you seen my black ...
dress ?
It 's a little wrinkled .
It 's fine .
â  ªâ  ª
Yeah . Thank you .
Kids don 't have strokes ...
unless they 're on drugs .
So , then , why the closed coffin ?
Oh , Ruthie .
I 'm so sorry .
( sniffles )
You all right , Dave ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
How are you ?
He sleeps all day .
He doesn 't move .
( dish clatters )
It 's too much for him .
It doesn 't make any sense , Rachel .
I spent four hours on the Internet
and I couldn 't find one single case
of a 16-year-old girl 's heart just stopping .
I spoke to three different doctors and not one of them
could tell me exactly what happened to my daughter .
( dish clatters )
( water stops running )
She was close ... ( sniffles ) with you .
And Aidan .
She confided in you .
Yeah , but she never said anything ...
nothing that would explain what happened .
But you could find out .
It 's what you do , isn 't it - -
ask questions ?
Rachel , please .
I saw her face .
TEENAGED GIRL : I knew Becca .
I mean , she was a little intense
but she wasn 't crazy .
They don 't put you in booties and a straightjacket
if you 're just freaked out .
Something scared the shit out of her .
Hi .
( music playing softly )
So , who 's in the mental hospital ?
Becca ... Katie 's friend .
Oh , right . She was the one who was ...
There when it happened .
So , what do you think they were doing up there ?
Oh , thanks .
I remember I was that age .
Me and my girlfriend used to
sneak up to my room , get high .
Do you think maybe she was into ... ?
TEENAGED BOY : It 's not about that .
It 's about the tape .
Kellen , don 't even .
What tape ?
The one that kills you when you watch it .
Oh , please .
What was on the tape ?
I haven 't seen it , obviously .
RACHEL : But Katie told you she saw this tape ?
Not Katie .
I heard it from her boyf ...
You heard it from who ?
She was dating this guy Josh .
He goes to Revere .
It was kind of a secret .
Kind of ?
Where is he - - Josh ? Is-Is he here ?
KELLEN : Josh is dead .
RACHEL : What ?
What happened ?
Supposedly , he killed himself ...
the same night that Katie died .
â  ªâ  ª
( eerie rumbling )
( rain falling outside )
Aidan ... what are you doing in here ?
Come on .
We shouldn 't be in her room .
It 's not her room anymore .
( rain continuing )
â  ªâ  ª
( sighs )
( traffic passing )
RACHEL : 10 : 00 p.m.
â  ªâ  ª
10 : 00 p.m.
RACHEL : Time of death , Wade
that 's all I want to know .
The name 's Katie Embrey .
Pull the report and read the time .
No , that 's okay . I 'll hold .
" Punctilious prick " ?
Nice alliteration , huh ?
You 're fired .
No , I 'm not .
Yes , you are .
I 'm cooking too good a story .
What is it ?
Yeah , I 'm still here .
Shh !
Okay , so what 's the time of death ?
â  ªâ  ª
( music fades )
( bell dings )
( door creaks )
Hi . I was wondering ...
Pick a card , any card .
Go ahead .
Okay , put it back .
Don 't let me see it .
That your card ?
No .
Damn .
I was wondering if you 'd remember someone
from a week ago .
Was there a problem ?
It 's my niece .
She sort of ran out
on her parents .
No .
I have some photos here .
That 's her and her friends .
I think they stayed here a night or so .
Yeah , they were in Cabin 12 .
They didn 't pay .
Had a number of complaints , about the TV , mainly .
Uh , reception 's never good here .
That 's why we bought
tape players for videos .
Quite a selection .
( scoffs )
Mostly they 're hand-me-downs
left by other guests .
Anyway , they didn 't pay .
And kids like that sometimes don 't .
Miss ?
You know , I 'm kind of tired .
I 'm thinking I might take a nap before I drive back .
( sniffles )
I 'll take Cabin 12 .
Hey .
This is your card , right ?
That 's it .
( insects chirping )
â  ªâ  ª
( electronic whirring )
( static )
( sighs )
( eerie humming and whining )
( whining stops )
( woman singing softly )
( eerie rumbling , hissing )
( gurgling )
( piercing whine )
( crackling )
( whine continues )
( static )
( whining fades )
( flute playing softly )
( eerie rumbling , hissing )
( static )
( wind blowing hollowly )
( electronic whirring )
( phone ringing )
( breathing heavily )
GIRL ( whispering ) : Seven days .
( breathing shakily )
â  ªâ  ª
( rain pelting )
( zipping )
I 'm going to school .
( breathing shakily )
( door closes )
Hold up .
RACHEL : What do you think ?
MAN : Well , it 's a pretty cool effect .
What does this have to do with the tape ?
Take my picture .
( whirring )
Are you going to look at me
at least ?
( camera beeps )
This the same camera ?
No . Scan the rest .
( beeping )
So , what do you think ?
Well , look , I thought you said this was about a tape .
( sighing )
I 'm thinking maybe you shouldn 't see it .
( chuckling )
No , I should know more about it first .
Well , isn 't that why I 'm here ?
So you can benefit from my wisdom ?
Four kids are dead , Noah .
Not from watching a videotape .
( clock ticking )
Come on , show it to me .
( eerie humming and whining )
( high-pitched screeching )
( traffic hum )
( man 's deep laughter )
â  ªâ  ª
( romantic music playing distantly )
( TV sports announcer shouting )
( indistinct dialogue on TV )
( door slides open )
Roll credits .
That was very student film .
I 'm sure it 's a lot ... scarier at night .
( phone ringing )
( breathing shakily )
( ringing continues )
You going to get that ?
( ringing stops )
So , you been working a lot ?
I 'm not tired , Noah .
Okay .
That tape didn 't scare you ?
No , not really . Sorry .
Four people are dead .
Yeah , but like I said , not from watching ...
Four people who watched it .
Come on , we watched it . We 're hanging .
It ... takes a week .
Right . Yeah , I 'm just going to go downtown .
I got to pick up some cameras from this guy
and then I got to prep this thing
that I may end up doing next week .
Noah ...
Hmm ?
Would you say that I 'm gullible ?
No .
Easily rattled ?
Definitely not .
I mean , you 're a little
highly strung maybe .
And you ain 't much of a dresser .
Who made it ?
Where 'd it come from ?
All right .
Make me a copy . I 'll see what I can do .
Thanks .
Yeah .
( door closes )
â  ªâ  ª
( beep )
( phones ringing , typewriters clacking )
( whirring )
( eerie humming and whining )
( woman singing softly )
( blipping , whirring )
â  ªâ  ª
( slight static burst )
( whirring )
You sure this is a copy ?
Yeah , why ?
The numbers are all screwed up .
The same problem got copied , I guess .
That 's impossible .
The numbers are the control track
they put on the tape whenever it 's recorded
which means theoretically
there shouldn 't be any images .
Hey , Noah , can you pretend for one minute
that I don 't read Video Geek Magazine ?
Okay , when you record a tape
the makeup of the tracks is like a signature
for whatever did the recording
like a camcorder , VCR , whatever .
So the control track could tell us where it came from .
But to not have one ...
I mean , that 's like being born without fingerprints .
Then , how did this get recorded ?
I don 't know .
But I 'm going to find out .
NOAH : All right , take a look .
You should be able to see the camera here
in the reflection .
The angle 's straight on , but you don 't .
Hmm . What 's that ?
It looks like she 's walking away
whoever she is .
No , I mean up there at the top .
Oh , no , that 's just the tracking .
I can fix that .
Whup , sorry .
Wait , go back .
There 's something there .
Yeah , you 're right .
There 's more picture .
Hold on .
I 'm going to stretch the alignment .
Yeah , it 's working .
It won 't go any further .
Keep going .
No , no , no , no , let me do it .
Wait , it won 't go any further .
It won 't go any further ! Get ...
Let me do it .
Shit !
Oh ...
( door opens )
Hey , Noah
I picked up the cameras .
They 're in really good shape .
Did you see the reprints I did
of that Guatemala stuff ?
' Cause they came out kind of ...
overexposed .
You working ?
This is a friend , Rachel Keller .
She writes for the " P.I. "
Rachel , this is Beth , my assistant .
Well , I prefer " partner in crime . "
( all chuckling )
She 's a journalism student at Kirkland , actually .
Well , I 'll stay out of your way .
I 'm not even here .
Rachel is researching a story . It 's this video hoax .
It 's sort of interesting . So you know video .
Why don 't you come take a look at this thing with the tracking .
RACHEL : You know , I 'm late .
I really should go .
Yeah , but why are you taking ... ?
I got to go .
It 's good to meet you .
( elevator grinding )
So you 're taking the tape ?
I don 't want her to see it .
Whoa . You don 't want her to see it ?
What about me seeing it ?
You had no problem showing it to me .
I did have a problem .
You 're angry .
I 'm not angry .
Oh , no ? What are you then ?
In a hurry .
( scoffs )
Look , I 'm sorry , but I 'm not going to get all worked up
over some high school rumor .
What are you thinking ?
I 'm thinking this is the part where I say
" You 're a flake who never finishes anything . "
Then you say I 'm " an obsessive bitch .
Needs to lighten up . "
Then I storm out
all pissed off , kicking myself for ever thinking
that you could just ...
grow up .
So , why don 't we just cut to that part right now
and save ourselves a lot of grief ?
All right .
Bye .
( eerie rumbling )
Watch out , missy .
Bad luck . You don 't need that .
( wheels squeaking and clicking )
( squeaking continues )
( game show plays on TV )
Becca ?
Becca .
We 're almost there .
HOST ( on TV ) : Summer , actually .
So circle gets that square .
We take a break , while you check this out .
This is how you can be part ...
RACHEL : Do you remember anything about that night ...
that night with Katie ?
Do you remember ...
how she died ?
Becca ?
She told you about a videotape , didn 't she ?
She was afraid , wasn 't she ?
Something was happening to her .
Becca ...
how did she die ?
Please .
I need to know .
And you will .
She 'll show you .
Who ?
Who will show me ?
Not now .
Four days .
WOMAN : Yeah , well , your home VCRs will give you a tracking window
but they won 't let you stretch it .
There 's no point , really , unless you 're talking restoration .
Archives will come in here
with these crummy old tapes sometimes .
Tracks totally shot - - servos can 't line them up .
But the big box here 's a warhorse .
Totally analog .
She 'll read to the very edge of your tape .
Just don 't force her or she 'll get pissy with you .
Your tracking , your monitor , your printer , if you need it .
So , uh ...
what are we watching , home movies or something ?
I 'd really rather watch it alone .
Really .
Whatever .
( whirring )
( sighs heavily )
Come on ...
( soft high-pitched humming )
Come on .
( humming intensifies )
Lighthouse .
Shit .
Hello ? Somebody ?
( tape deck whirring )
( grunting softly )
Damn .
( slow whirring )
â  ªâ  ª
Something you needed help with ?
( fly buzzes )
Hey , you ... you got a ... ya ...
Well , that seems to be the lot of it .
Thank you .
( pages turning )
( sighing )
â  ªâ  ª
" Moesko Island . "
( sighs quietly )
( eerie rumbling )
( printer whirring )
" Anna Morgan . "
â  ªâ  ª
Oh , my God .
( books and papers thudding )
( grunting )
â  ªâ  ª
" Mysterious Sickness Strikes Morgan Ranch Horses .
" Investigators search for answers
after second horse drowning . "
( eerie rumbling )
( rhythmic clicking )
( whispering ) : " Anna Morgan . "
" Horses Recovering After Breeder 's Suicide . "
( rapid scratching )
" ... suffered from hallucinations . "
" Eola ... County Psychiatric . "
( intense scratching )
What happened to you , Anna ?
â  ªâ  ª
Pack of Double Lights . Thanks , Lani .
( register beeps )
$ 15.33 .
You 're gonna die .
My cousin was two packs a day .
Used the patch ... never looked back .
All right , well , I 'll keep that in mind .
Have a nice day .
You , too .
( eerie rumbling )
( indistinct arguing in background )
( unearthly whistling )
( sighs heavily )
( keys clank )
( static hisses on TV )
( shrieks )
( anxious laugh )
Hi .
Sorry I 'm late .
Uh ... mmm ... no . No problem .
Everything okay ?
Oh , yeah . He was an angel .
I-I ... went in to tell him that it was bedtime
and he was already under the covers .
And then he read me a bedtime story .
Um ... ( clears throat )
he learned the word " conundrum . "
Really ?
Yeah . And then ... he drew my picture .
Well , here you go .
Thanks .
Sure .
( rain falling outside )
( rainfall continues )
( door creaking )
Hey , Ruthie , it 's me .
I 'm sorry to call so late , but I need a favor .
I have to go upstate to do this story
and I need you to watch Aidan for me .
RUTHIE ( on phone ) : Oh , Rachel , I don 't know .
How long will you be gone ?
It 's just for two days , I promise .
This isn 't the best time for me .
( coughing )
Rachel ? Rachel , are you there ?
Hold on a sec ... Sorry .
( coughing and gasping )
Rachel ?
Is this about Katie ?
( retching )
( retching and gasping )
Ruthie ...
( eerie rumbling )
( gasping )
Aidan ?
( eerie rumbling )
( unearthly screeching )
( gasping )
( panting )
( panting slows )
( rainfall outside )
( deep rumbling )
( grunts )
No !
( static hissing )
Why , baby , why ? Why ? !
I couldn 't sleep .
Who is she , Rachel ?
( phone ringing )
( ringing stops )
( gasping )
( ringing )
Leave him alone !
NOAH ( on phone ) : Rachel ?
( sobs )
Noah ...
L-Listen to me . R-Rachel ...
I need to talk to you , okay ?
I ...
I believe you .
Rachel , you there ?
( quiet sobbing )
He ... He watched the tape .
Who ? Who watched it ?
( sobs )
Our son .
( unearthly whistling )
( rain pattering )
You took my picture .
I 've seen you .
When I 'm in the yard at school .
You 're there .
You wish I was around more ?
No .
Do you want to be around more ?
Rachel and I were ...
Young .
Mom 's told me that story .
The thing is , I ...
I don 't think I 'd make a good father .
Maybe it was because my own was ...
such a ... disappointment .
Thing is , I don 't want anyone else to do it , either .
Be your father .
It 's a conundrum .
( laughs )
Yeah , it is .
( paper crackling )
( pages turning )
( rain falling )
( door opening )
Time to go , mister .
I 'm not finished .
Noah said to make one for you .
RACHEL : You could almost draw a line through her life .
On one side , there 's this happy woman
who spends her time with her husband , riding horses
everything sheltered , protected and comfortable .
Her face , there 's ... light , there 's pride .
And then , one day , something happens
and she takes this hard corner and the light ... goes out
and then she ends up at Eola County Psychiatric
all alone .
NOAH : What happened to her ?
I don 't know yet
but I think it has something to do with the horses .
I think we should go to the island together .
It 's Tuesday , Noah .
I only have one day left .
I need you to go to the hospital
and find out as much as you can about Anna .
The images on the tape are leading us somewhere .
Katie saw them all , too .
I think ... before you die
you see the ring .
( wipers clacking )
Shit !
Hey , Rach ! Wait !
( rain splattering )
( bell clanging )
( ferry engine roaring )
â  ªâ  ª
A daughter ?
( ferry engines rumbling smoothly )
( footsteps approaching )
( chuckles softly )
Hey , you .
( nickers )
Ooh .
It 's okay .
I 'm not going to hurt you .
Yeah .
Easy , boy .
( nickering )
That 's it .
( whinnying nervously )
Hey , boy .
I 'm not going to hurt you .
( whinnying frantically )
It 's okay . Calm down .
( whinnying )
Somebody !
( whinnies )
( whinnying )
Jesus Christ !
( whinnies )
Somebody , help !
( grunting )
Daddy , my horse !
Whoa ! Whoa ! Whoa !
( horse whinnying )
He 's going out !
Over here !
Whoa ! Whoa ! Easy !
Come on .
( snorting )
( yelling )
( whinnying )
No , down ! No !
( grunting and gasping )
( snorting )
( whinnying )
( gasps )
( whimpering )
( whinnying )
( panting )
â  ªâ  ª
( screaming )
( horn blowing )
( speaking indistinctly )
I need to see the records
for a patient named Anna Morgan .
Are you a relative ?
Well , no .
I 'm sorry , sir .
We 're a mental health facility .
Our records are private .
Well , she 's been dead 24 years .
I don 't think she 'll mind .
I 'm sorry .
It 's impossible .
Look ...
I 've seen them before .
I 've been up there .
MAN : Nice try .
The record rooms are downstairs , guy .
( chuckles softly )
You win .
( grunting )
Jerk off !
â  ªâ  ª
( fly buzzing )
Are you in here , Anna ?
â  ªâ  ª
Hello ?
( eerie rumbling )
â  ªâ  ª
( hammering )
( hammering continuing )
Excuse me , Mr. Morgan .
I was wondering if you 'd have a moment to speak with me .
My name 's Rachel Keller .
I 'm a writer with the " Seattle P.I. "
You want to know about the horses .
I didn 't mean to ...
It 's just I wasn 't able to find a number to reach you .
Every now and then , a writer comes along ...
heard about what happened .
What 's left to write about , though , I don 't know .
I was hoping you had just a few minutes .
Well , work never ends around here , really ...
but I guess I got a few .
So , what is it you 're writing , miss ?
About horses in general
or just those that go strange ?
I read you had to put so many down .
Most put themselves down .
They drowned .
How 'd they get out ?
They just broke
through the fences and ran to the shore .
So , they went crazy ?
It would seem so , yes ...
or maybe they just sense things before we do .
So , where are your horses now ?
I don 't breed anymore .
I guess you wouldn 't ...
not after what happened .
That must 've been hard ... on both of you ...
you and your wife .
( thunder rumbling )
I 'm sorry , miss , what 's your name again ?
Rachel .
Well , Rachel ...
you want to tell me what 's really on your mind ?
Do you know what this is ?
I think it 's a message ...
from your wife .
Anna 's on this tape .
She 's right there in that room .
You can see the lighthouse , the horses ...
Where 'd you get that ?
Shelter Mountain Inn .
Is that the only one ?
I made a copy .
( sighs )
I 've got a lot of work to do today ...
a lot of acres out there .
Minute I think I 'm done with one thing
another thing needs fixing .
You don 't want to see this tape ?
You 're not even curious ?
Curious ?
No . I don 't think so .
Mr. Morgan ...
I can 't help you .
Where 's your daughter ?
Maybe she could help ...
I don 't have a daughter .
Excuse me ?
What is it with reporters ?
You take one person 's tragedy
and force the world to experience it ...
spread it like sickness .
Mr. Morgan ...
Tell me , miss ...
what is it you think you know ?
Then leave it alone .
( slams )
( sighs )
â  ªâ  ª
( rope creaking )
( banging )
( whispering ) : Anna .
" Anna Morgan 's
Hallucinations " ?
What 's wrong with you ?
" ' 65 , conceived . "
" ' 65 , miscarriage . "
" ' 66 , conceived . "
" ' 66 , miscarriage . "
Christ , she wouldn 't give up .
( file falls on floor )
â  ªâ  ª
" Sessions terminated ... at father 's request .
See Video Record S-M-0-1-5 . "
( phone ringing )
( grinding furiously )
RUTH : Aidan ?
Aidan , it 's your mom .
( Aidan over telephone ) : Hi , Mom .
Honey , the house you drew for me ...
Uh-huh ?
... where did you see it ?
Did you see it in your head ?
Is that why you drew it ?
In my head ?
Aidan ... why did you draw that house ?
Because she told me to .
Who ?
Who told you to ?
The little girl .
She talks to you ?
No .
She shows me things .
Did she show you the horses ?
She doesn 't like it in the barn .
The horses keep her up at night .
So , she still lives there ?
No .
( whispering ) : She lives in a dark place now .
( clock ticking )
( puzzle pieces clicking )
( ticking loudly )
( door opening )
WOMAN : You 're getting a little old
to be crabbing out there , Cal .
Your body 's about outlived its warranty , you know .
You ain 't exactly the catch of the day .
Oh ... let 's see you catch one better !
CAL : Yeah ...
Good afternoon .
I 'm Dr. Grasnik .
I think he was here before me .
Darby ? Darby 's always here .
Aren 't you , Darby ?
He 's my son 's boy .
Come over on the ferry , did you ?
Yes .
Um ... have you lived here long ?
Born and raised .
Only doctor on the island .
Then you know the Morgans and their daughter .
Do you know their daughter ?
( clock ticking continuing )
What 's this about ?
Look , I 'm sorry .
I-I don 't know how to say this
but I 'm seeing things in my head - - images - -
and so is my son .
My son , that ... that 's why I 'm here
and somehow , I don 't know how , but ...
it 's because of that girl .
Haven 't heard anybody say that in a long time .
( squeaking loudly )
She wanted a child more than anything .
Poor Anna .
They tried hard for years
but sometimes it 's just not meant to be .
Then one winter , they went away .
When they came back
it was with Samara .
Adopted , they said .
Never did say from where .
Said the mother had died of complications .
But they had their baby , they had their horses - -
everything was fine ...
till Anna started coming to see me .
Said she was suffering visions ...
seeing things ...
horrible things ...
like they 'd been burned inside her .
That it only happened around Samara ...
that the girl put them there .
( merry-go-round squeaking continues )
Were you Samara 's doctor , too ?
Was there anything wrong with her ?
You mean medically ?
I mean whatever you mean .
( squeaking continuing )
When Darby there was born ...
we knew something wasn 't right with him ...
but we loved him anyway .
Takes work , you know .
Some people have limits .
So , what happened to her ?
I referred them to Eola Psychiatric
on the mainland .
I assume she 's still there .
You don 't know ?
How can you not know ?
We 've been through ...
a lot of hard years out here ...
mean winters ...
small hauls , no fish ...
and that was long before the horses .
See , when you live on an island
you catch a cold , it 's everybody 's cold .
No offense , ma 'am
but what the hell does that mean ?
It means ever since that girl 's been gone
things have been better .
( squeaking continuing )
MAN : 1978 .
Man , we 're really going back in time here .
Yeah , the lady at reception said it should still be here .
Should be . You say you 're the patient 's father , right ?
Yep . Richard Morgan , that 's me .
What is your secret ?
Diet and exercise , man .
No shit !
Yeah , that 's all it takes .
You know , I 'm not an idiot .
You try and walk out of here with my file
and I 'll be on you like white on rice .
You understand ?
No , man .
I just want to watch it .
I 'm responsible for every file tape in here .
I have a system ... and I don 't want anyone
disarranging it .
I 'd never ... disarrange ...
Long as we understand each other .
Okay , now I 'm mad .
Does it say who was the last person to watch it ?
Yeah .
It was you .
Come on , come on !
( cell phone beeping )
( man over phone ) : The mobile unit you 've called is not responding
or is outside the coverage area .
You piece of shit !
( beeping )
( sighs )
Come on , Rachel .
( crickets chirping )
Hello ?
( door creaking )
Mr. Morgan ?
â  ªâ  ª
( doors rattling )
( eerie rumbling )
( inhales slowly )
( exhales slowly )
( clock ticking )
( ticking continues )
( gasps )
( shudders )
( tape machine whirring )
MAN ( on tape ) : This is SM0015
Samara Morgan , hour 14 .
Good . Very good .
So , what is it that 's keeping you awake ?
You must sleep sometime .
Do you dream about something ?
Samara ?
Let 's talk about the pictures .
How did you make them ?
Samara ?
How did you make these pictures ?
I don 't ...
make them .
I see them ...
and then ...
they just ... are .
MAN : Samara ...
I need you to start telling me the truth , okay ?
Can I see my mommy ?
No , Samara .
Not until we understand what 's wrong with you .
I love my mommy .
Yes , you do .
But you don 't want to hurt her anymore , now , do you ?
You don 't want to hurt anyone .
But I do , and I 'm sorry .
It won 't stop .
Well , that 's why you 're here .
So that I can help you to make it stop .
He 's going to leave me here .
Who ?
Daddy .
They just want to help you .
Not Daddy .
Your daddy loves you .
Daddy loves the horses .
He wants me to go away .
No , he doesn 't .
But he doesn 't know ...
He doesn 't know what ?
Samara ?
( static hissing )
She 's never gonna whisper in my fucking ear ever again !
What did you do to her ?
She was your daughter !
You killed Samara , didn 't you ?
You killed her , and when your wife - -
My wife was not supposed to have a child !
Mr. Morgan ... What are you doing ?
The whispers ... you could hear them all the time .
At night . In your sleep .
Even the damn horses .
Mr. Morgan , come out of there .
And those pictures .
Oh , Good Christ .
The things she 'd show you .
She 's still showing them .
And she 'll never stop .
You coming here proves that .
Where is she ? Please .
I have to stop her .
If I don 't , my son will die !
Oh , yes .
He will .
She never sleeps .
Wait . No ...
No !
( screaming )
Rachel ! Shh ! Shh !
It 's all right !
Shh , shh , shh , shh , shh .
It 's okay . It 's okay .
You 're okay .
Shh , shh , shh !
You okay ?
NOAH : Oh , Jesus .
( gasping )
AIDAN : She doesn 't like the barn .
The horses keep her up at night .
She doesn 't like the barn .
What ?
The horses keep her awake .
( doors creaking )
( crickets chirping )
â  ªâ  ª
( whispering ) : Samara ...
He kept her here .
Her mother was going crazy .
Morgan blamed the child .
So he kept her here .
Alone .
Not alone .
â  ªâ  ª
Rachel ...
There 's something under here .
It looks like it 's etched into the wood .
Or burned .
( wallpaper ripping )
â  ªâ  ª
I 've seen this tree before .
Yeah , it was on the tape .
No .
I 've been there .
Shelter Mountain .
â  ªâ  ª
RACHEL : The sun came through the leaves , lit them up like it was on fire .
Right at sunset .
Right when I watched the tape .
That was a week ago .
( sighs heavily )
We 're back to where we started from .
Something led us here .
The tree , the drawing on the wall - -
It doesn 't matter .
We 're too late .
You have to help him .
What are you talking about ?
Aidan .
It 's up to you now .
Just use the time you have and figure something out .
We 'll figure this out together , right now !
It 's too late , Noah !
Stop it , okay ? There 's a reason that we 're here !
What ? !
I don 't know , okay ?
There 's something in this room !
I mean , it 's in this phone !
It 's in this television !
Come on !
Tell us now , why don 't you ? !
( grunts )
( clattering )
Noah ...
look .
( clacking )
â  ªâ  ª
( grunting with effort )
( grunting )
( Noah panting )
( eerie rumbling )
( stone scraping )
( both panting )
Aw , Jesus .
How far down do you think it goes ?
I can 't see anything .
( staticky blurts )
We should drop something .
( static hissing )
( scraping )
( both breathing deeply )
( rock hitting bottom )
Do you think she 's down there ?
Shh ...
( deep rumbling )
( squeaking )
( thunderous whooshing )
( screaming )
( echoing ) : Rachel !
( fly buzzing )
( water gurgling and bubbling )
( gasping )
Rachel !
( Rachel coughing and gasping )
I 'm here !
I 'm all right !
( quietly ) : I think .
I 'll go find something to get you out !
Hurry !
( gasping )
( water dripping )
( eerie screeching )
Noah ?
( stone scraping )
( grunting )
Noah ?
Noah !
( static blips )
( grunting )
( eerie rumbling )
( yells )
Oh !
( gasping )
( panting )
( eerie screaming )
( Samara singing )
â  ª Here we go â  ª
â  ª The world is spinning â  ª
â  ª When it stops â  ª
â  ª It 's just beginning. â  ª
ANNA : Isn 't it beautiful here , Samara ?
So peaceful .
I know things will get better .
( breath quivering )
All I ever wanted was you .
( eerie rumbling )
( low rumbling )
( gasps )
( panting )
She was still alive .
Where did you go ?
( gasping )
( panting )
It 's okay now .
It 's okay .
NOAH : Rachel !
Rachel , the sun 's set !
The sun has set !
It 's past sunset .
Do you hear me ?
It 's past sunset !
Rachel ?
Rachel , are you there ?
( shivering )
I 'm here .
( speaking indistinctly )
They 're going to bury her next week .
It 's over .
You okay ?
She wanted that child
more than anything in the world .
How could she have done that ?
She just wanted to be heard .
Sometimes children ...
yell or cry or draw pictures .
â  ªâ  ª
I want to go home .
I can 't imagine being stuck down a well all alone like that .
How long could you survive ?
Seven days .
You could survive for seven days .
â  ªâ  ª
( rain falling )
Come on .
Hey .
â  ªâ  ª
Why don 't you just call me sometime ?
Unless you 're renting a movie .
( chuckles )
( sighs )
Call me tomorrow
and the day after that .
â  ªâ  ª
( murmurs )
Rachel ?
Hmm ?
What time is it ?
It 's either really late or really early ...
depending on how you look at it .
Don 't you have to be at work ?
Not today .
What happened to the girl ?
Samara ?
Is that her name ?
Mm-hmm .
Is she still in the dark place ?
No .
We set her free .
You helped her ?
Yeah .
Why did you do that ?
What 's wrong , honey ?
You weren 't supposed to help her .
It 's okay now .
She 's not going to hurt you .
She ...
Don 't you understand , Rachel ?
She never sleeps .
( TV static blaring )
( static continuing )
( static stops )
( static hissing )
( ringing )
Pick up the phone , Noah .
Come on , pick up .
( phone ringing )
( static hissing )
( ringing continuing )
â  ªâ  ª
( eerie whirring )
( ringing continuing )
( tires squealing )
RACHEL : Come on , Noah !
Pick up the goddamn phone !
( horn honking )
( tires squealing )
( trickling )
( phone ringing )
( gasping )
( ringing continuing )
( grunting )
( screaming )
( static blaring )
( brakes squealing )
( panting )
Come on !
( phone ringing )
( static hissing )
( ringing continuing )
( ringing through )
( static hissing continues )
( glass crunching )
( hissing continues )
( sighs )
( screaming )
( screaming echoing )
( panting and crying )
( thud )
( elevator whirring )
( sobbing )
Go to your room !
Now !
( breathing anxiously )
What do you want ?
What do you want from me ?
( crying )
( sobbing )
Why not me ?
What did I do that he didn 't ?
( fire crackling )
â  ªâ  ª
( echoing ) : She just wanted to be heard .
He wants me to go away .
My wife was not supposed to have a child !
ANNA : All I ever wanted was you .
AIDAN : Don 't you understand , Rachel ?
But he doesn 't know .
She never sleeps .
MORGAN : You take one person 's tragedy
and force the world to experience it .
You spread it like sickness .
MAN : You don 't want to hurt anyone .
But I do .
And I 'm sorry .
It won 't stop .
RACHEL : I made a copy .
Push it in .
" Play . "
Push .
( high-pitched electronic whining )
It 's going to keep killing , isn 't it ?
She 'll never stop .
Don 't worry , sweetie .
You 're going to be okay .
What about the person we show it to ?
What happens to them ?
( static hissing )
( static blaring )
( music box playing )
CHILD : â  ª Here we go â  ª
â  ª The world is spinning â  ª
â  ª When it stops â  ª
â  ª It 's just beginning â  ª
â  ª Sun comes up â  ª
â  ª We laugh and we cry â  ª
â  ª Sun goes down â  ª
â  ª And then we all die. â  ª